这里唯一的问题
And the only thing wrong-
美国梦的唯一问题就在于
The only thing wrong with the American dream...
有这样的人  有太多这样的人
is people- too many people-
我们中有太多人告诉年轻人
too many of us telling young people
美国梦已不复存在
that the dream is dead.
当我还在特伦顿的贫民窟时
They told me that
他们就这样告诫我
when I was growing up in the slums of Trenton.
事实证明他们是错的
And they were wrong.
当我只有58美元存款
They told me that
却决定竞选参议员时
when I decided to run for senator,
他们就这样告诫我
with only $58 in my savings account.
事实证明他们是错的
And they were wrong.
而今  他们依然如此告诫我
And they are still telling me that now-
我不可能成功  因为我是黑人
that I don't have a chance because I'm black,
因为我没有高耸的鼻梁
because I don't have the right nose,
因为我依然只有58美元存款
because I still only have $58 in my savings account.
但有你们在  我们就可以让梦想继续
With your help, we can keep that dream alive.
最后
And in closing,
我
just...
只想说
let me say-
我想说  大家都应该行动起来
Let me say that you should all donate the legal maximum...
捐出你的最大限额给下一任美国总统
to the next president of the United States.
你还好吗  要喝水吗
Are you okay? Do you need some water or something?
不用  我没事
No. I'm fine.
我没事  真的
I'm fine, really.
您仪表堂堂
Handsome guy like you,
我敢说七成的女性会选您
I bet you get 70% of the women.
希望如此吧
Well, here's hoping.
肯定会的  再加上您妻子死于癌症
Of course, it helps your wife died of cancer.
我是说  节哀顺变
I mean, I'm sorry,
但同情票非您莫属
but the sympathy vote's in your pocket.
是的  感谢你的支持
Yeah, I appreciate your support.
参议员  我的工会拥有大量竞选基金
Listen, Senator, my union has a hell of a war chest.
我向来很支持工会
I've always been strong on the union.
问题是
The thing is,
您总是在演讲里反复提到工人
you always go on in your speeches about the workers...
印尼的  柬埔寨的  马里的
in Indonesia, Cambodia, Timbuktu.
因为我们要有道义上...
Because I think we have a- a moral-
我的工会成员们很受伤
My union members are hurting.
他们不关心这个
They don't care about
道义对他们来说一文不值  你还好吗
moral this and moral that. Are you all right?
参议员
Senator?
记者们该高兴了==
The guys are gonna love that.
大家散开  给他空间呼吸
Everyone, give him some room. Give him room to breathe!
请后退  参议员  你还好吗
Back off, please! Senator, are you all right?
参议员感觉恶心
The senator's suffering from nausea,
头疼  神志不清
headache and mental confusion.
吃了变质的寿司也要找我来
Ah, bad sushi is so hard to diagnose.
别犯傻了
You're being childish.
就算这个病例像你想的那样无关紧要
Look, if his case is as trivial as you think,
也只需三分钟就能搞定
it'll take you three minutes to diagnose.
三分钟我也可以干点别的
Three minutes that I could
坐在马桶上看点带色的东西
spend sitting on the toilet with the funny pages.
-你对我有意见  -没有
- You're mad at me. - Nope.
反正我也不喜欢卡梅隆和福曼
I never liked Cameron or Foreman.
知道为什么我要让你解雇他们其中一个吗
You know why I'm forcing you to fire one of them?
因为你必须向我证明你有团队精神
Because you need to prove to me that you're a team player.
如果你接手这个病例
Now, if you did that,
就不必经受这次考验了
you wouldn't need to go through this exercise.
好  参议员吐的时候我会托住他的头发
Fine. I'll hold the senator's hair while he upchucks.
还有
By the way,
我要你在全国心脏病学会议上做一次发言
I need you to give a speech at the National Cardiology Conference,
时间是下周
um, next week.
我不做发言的  我很害羞的
I don't do speeches. I'm shy.
东溪制药公司研发出了一种
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals has developed
新型血管紧张素转换酶抑制剂
a new ACE inhibitor.
我希望你能宣传一下
I would like you to extol
这一突破性药物的良效
the virtues of this breakthrough medication.
东溪制药公司吗
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals?
等等  那是我的公司吗
Wait a second? Don't I own that company?
哦不是  那是你的公司
Oh, no, that's right. You do.
维普里尔相对于其前身各方面都有极大提升
Viopril is a significant improvement over the old version.
其优点都写在研究报告里
It's all there in the study.
我只知道它的价格倒是有很大提升
I know its price tag is significantly improved.
你有两个选择
You can either give one
要么做一个十分钟的报告和三分钟的诊断
10-minute talk and one three-minute diagnosis,
要么扔掉一只你的小鸭子
or you can fire one of your pets.
以我看来
My understanding was that
你是一个理智至上的人
you believed in rationality above all else.
维普里尔
Viopril.
很感谢你们没让媒体进来
I appreciate your keeping the media away.
你的手下也进不来
We're keeping your staff away as well.
可以放松点了
Take it easy now.
我正在竞选
I'm in the middle of a campaign.
我们越快把你治好
The faster we can get you better,
你才能尽快离开这里
the faster you can get out of here.
筹款会上的其他人里有生病的吗
Anyone else at the fund-raiser get sick?
没有  而且我觉得不是传染病
I don't think so, and I don't think that's it.
几个星期以来我一直感觉不适
I've been under the weather for weeks.
四处奔走所致  我下周还得去苏丹
Lots of traveling. I'm supposed to be in the Sudan next week.
有助于我集中注意力
Helps me concentrate.
比药片还有效
Even better than drugs.
请张嘴
Open your mouth, please.
这疤痕挺大的
That's quite a scar.
那是我六岁的时候
When I was six,
从秋千上摔下来咬到舌头了
I fell off the swing and bit my tongue.
后来很久说话都不利索
Couldn't talk right for the longest time.
被人嘲笑
Lots of teasing.
因此我更加坚定地斗争
It just made me fight harder,
为那些无力抗争的人争取权益
speak up for those who can't.
长鼻子呀长鼻子
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
舌头愈合很快
Tongues heal too fast.
你的智囊团编的故事挺不错
Your political consultants have written you a nice story.
单靠这个小故事
In a tight race,
就能助你在拉锯战中占得先机
the lispers alone could put you over the top.
你是共和党呢  还是敌视一切政客
You a Republican, or you just hate all politicians?
我只是觉得被逼着听人胡扯很烦人
I just find being forced to sit through drivel annoying.
你觉得真诚很烦人吗
You find sincerity annoying?
你是从贫民窟走出来的黑人
You're a black kid from the ghetto...
最终进入了耶鲁法学院和美国参议院
who made it to Yale Law and the United States Senate.
这个故事已经够梦幻了
That's a sufficiently mythical story.
不用再拿舌头的故事故弄玄虚了
You don't need to lie about your tongue.
肯定敲错位置了
Must've missed it.
怎么了
What's wrong?
怎么回事
What is it?
问题不在吃的东西上  在你的大脑里
It's not the food. It's your brain.
安排磁共振成像  还有腰椎穿刺
Get an M.R.I. And a lumbar puncture.
取消你的出行计划
Cancel your travel plans.
腰椎穿刺没发现感染
The senator's L.P. showed no sign of infection,
磁共振成像没发现异常
and the M.R.I. looks fairly clean.
那我们可以告诉他一切正常  可以出院了
I guess we can tell him he's fairly healthy and can go home.
但在布罗卡区有个东西
Well, there is something in Broca's area,
很小  也不明显
but it's small, low intensity.
估计是背景噪音吧
Most likely just background noise.
愿意用你的工作打包票吗
Care to bet your job on that?
那是什么表情
What was that?
你说什么啊
What was what?
你恼怒了  刚才明显是恼怒的表情
You got annoyed. That was clearly an annoyed face.
你拿我们的未来当儿戏我就会恼怒
I get annoyed by glib remarks about our futures.
上周你就没有这样
Last week you didn't get annoyed.
你吓得屁滚尿流  真奇怪
You made poopie in your pants. It's weird.
就好像你知道了没什么可担心了一样
It's almost like now you know you have nothing to worry about.
奇斯没什么可担心了吗
Chase has nothing to worry about?
你们都不用担心了
None of you has anything to worry about.
怎么回事
What happened?
沃格勒认识到自己办事方法上的错误
Vogler saw the error of his ways
已经忏悔了
and repented.
这个伤口可能什么也不是
The lesion could be nothing.
也可能是脑瘤或是感染
Also could be a brain tumor or an infection.
只有一个办法能确定
There's only one way to find out which.
你想开颅吗
You want to cut into his brain?
我知道这很危险
Dangerous, I know.
尤其他又是个政客
Especially since he's a politician,
脑子里肯定曲里拐弯的
his brain's all twisted.
但这和午饭之前就中风比起来
But I weighed that against the risk of him
总要好一些  通知手术室  安排手术
stroking out before lunch. Call Surgery. Get it scheduled.
-你没有怀孕  -早就告诉你了
- You're not pregnant. - Well, I told you that.
但我这里一直流血总有个原因吧
There's got to be some other reason I'm still spotting.
当然  你怀过孕
Sure. You were pregnant.
从你的激素水平看  你流产了
Based on your hormone levels, you've had a miscarriage.
我都没有约会
I haven't even been on a date.
是啊  没人请你吃饭
Right. And since it's physically
你怎么可能跟人做爱呢
impossible to have sex without someone buying you dinner-
自从我和丈夫分开以后就没有过性生活
I haven't had sex since I split up with my husband.
都已经一年多了
That was almost a year ago.
好吧  随你怎么说
Fine. Have it your way.
怀上耶稣了吧
Immaculate conception.
天主教信条谓圣母玛利亚蒙天恩
而无原罪怀孕的无沾成胎说
-我怎么办  -还用问吗
- Um, what do I do? - Well, it's obvious.
自己建个教呗
Start a religion.
来我办公室
In my office.
午后缠绵  她就是喜欢这根硬棒子
Afternoon delight. She just loves the hard wood.
你不能只因为磁共振成像上的一个斑
You're not doing a brain biopsy
就进行脑部活检
based on a spot on an M.R.I.
你怎么知道的
Where'd you get that?
至少不能在美国参议员身上
Not on a United States senator.
也就是说  如果他是个看大门的
Oh, just so I'm clear, if he was a janitor,
就可以做啦  你能列个名单不
that would be okay? Do you have a list?
脑部活检可能会导致永久的神经损伤
A brain biopsy can cause permanent neurological damage.
对哦  肿瘤对大脑益处多多
Whereas tumors are really good for brains.
让它们茁壮成长吧
Make 'em grow big and strong.
-这事我说了算  -你说了不算
- It's my call. - No, it's not.
你要给病人分三六九等吗
You're pulling rank on patient care?
这事我也做不了主
It's not my call either.
-你来决定  -要么是肿瘤
- It's up to you. - Either it's a tumor
要么就是腰椎穿刺没有检测出来的感染
or it's an infection that the lumbar puncture didn't pick up.
不管是哪种  如果不及时治疗都会致命
Either way, unless we treat it immediately, it could kill you.
也可能什么也不是
Or it could be nothing.
脑部磁共振成像原本就不精确
Reading brain M.R.I.'s is not an exact science.
那我的症状是由什么导致的
Well, what caused my s-symptoms?
这问题问的好
Wow! Excellent question.
很多医生都想不到这一层
Many doctors wouldn't have gone there.
可能只是短暂性脑缺血
It could be a transient ischemic attack.
你可以发表一份声明
You could make the argument
需要暂时入院观察一段时间
for watching carefully for the time being.
可是只有行政人员遮掩丑闻的时候
Hmm, but you'd only make that argument
才会发表这种声明
if you were an administrator covering your ass.
那太可笑了而且有辱斯文
That's absurd and insulting.
辱的就是斯文
Insulting, yes.
选民们会怎么想
What would the voters think?
要是他们发现我做了脑...脑部活检
If they find out I've had a b-brain biopsy?
这可能会留下脑...脑部损伤
This could leave you b-b-b-brain damaged,
你却还在担心那帮白人乡巴佬
and you're worried about NASCAR dads?
这不是脑瘤
It's not a brain tumor.
也不是细菌感染
It's not a bacterial infection either.
也就是说活检什么也没检出来
So you biopsied his brain for nothing?
如果真是这样
If that were true,
威尔森医生的嘴会张成那副鬼样子吗
would Dr.Wilson's mouth be contorted into that ugly shape?
是弓浆虫病
It's toxoplasmosis.
你确定吗
You sure?
也就是说伟大的黑人福音得了艾滋病
Which means the Great Black Hope has full-blown AIDS.
这在迪比克[民主党居多]肯定会引起轰动
They're gonna love that in Dubuque.
弓浆虫是一种很常见的真菌
Toxoplasmosis is a fairly common fungus you can get...
吃了不熟的肉类
from eating under-cooked meat
或是触摸猫粪便都有可能染上
or touching cat feces.
在很小的几率下
In rare cases, the fungi travel
真菌会随血液流向大脑并附着
up the bloodstream and latch onto the brain,
导致损伤或是炎症反应
causing a lesion or inflammation.
那能不能治愈
So, what's the prognosis?
弓浆虫通常都可以治愈
Toxo usually responds to treatment,
但它只在一种情况下导致脑损伤
but it only causes a lesion in your brain
就是你的免疫系统原本已经很羸弱了
if your immune system is extremely weak to begin with.
参议员先生  恐怕您患上了艾滋病
Senator, I'm afraid you have AIDS.
我相信
As I'm sure-
-不可能  -我相信您知道
- No! - As I'm sure you know,
患上艾滋以后也能活很长时间
people with H.I.V. can live a long time.
还有什么其他的可能
What else could do this to me?
理论上说  也可能是某种癌症
Theoretically, certain cancers.
大脑里有弓浆虫就必然是艾滋病
If you have toxo in your brain, you have AIDS.
我没有得艾滋病
I do not have AIDS.
我从没注...注...注射过毒品
I don't sh- sh- shoot up drugs.
也从没嫖...嫖过
I don't s-sleep with-
我知道这是个噩耗  我也很同情你
This is very bad news. I get that, and I sympathize.
但你得快点渡过心理抵制期
But we gotta speed through the denial phase
因为你需要尽快服用抗逆转录病毒药物
because you need antiretrovirals and you need them fast.
可你们根本没给我做HIV检测
But-you haven't even tested me for H.I.V.!
-会做的  -但弓浆虫药物会惊扰真菌
- We will. - But the toxo drugs are gonna piss off your fungi.
一旦真菌动怒以后
And when fungi get pissed-
我不会吃这种药
I am not going to take the pills.
你害怕会传扬出去
You're afraid word will leak out.
相信我  不管传不传扬你都当不了总统
Trust me. You're not gonna be president either way.
之所以叫白宫可不仅仅是因为墙面的颜色
They don't call it the White House because of the paint job.
你们接下来要做的就是
Here's what you're gonna do.
给我服用专治弓浆虫病的药物
You're gonna give me the drugs for the toxo only.
用化名替我做HIV测试
You're going to test me for H.I.V., under a false name.
检测癌症
You are going to test me for cancer...
和其他任何可能的病因
and anything else that could have done this to me.
如果得了癌症  我会配合治疗
If I have cancer, I will deal with it.
但我绝不会
But I do not...
得艾滋病
have AIDS.
东溪制药公司很高兴向大家宣布
"Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals are pleased to announce...
格利高里·豪斯医生将出席研讨会
that Dr. Gregory House will present
报告全新血管紧张素转换酶抑制剂的最新进展
the latest research on our exciting new ACE inhibitor."
你瞎编的吧  那可是沃格勒的公司
You're making that up. That's Vogler's company.
官方消息
Press release.
他将在北美心脏病学会议上做报告
"During an address at the North American Cardiology Conference."
豪斯从不做报告
House never gives speeches.
只要我有心
But when I really believe in something-
该死的  我就有办法逆转乾坤
Gosh dang it, I got a chance to make a difference here.
你和沃格勒做交易了
You made a deal with Vogler?
最近流行交易  大家都在做
It's all the rage. Everybody's doing it.
什么样的交易
So, what's the deal?
你替他卖狗皮膏药就可以把我们留下
You get to keep all of us if you flog his products?
一个报告而已  没什么
One speech. No biggie.
福曼在做骨髓活检测试癌症
Foreman's doing a bone marrow biopsy to check for cancer.
癌症  参议员得的是艾滋
Cancer? The senator's got AIDS.
癌症写在报纸上更好看一些
Cancer sounds better in a press release.
你们快点做酶联免疫吸附  检测HIV
I need you guys to rush the ELISA test for H.I.V.
谢谢你
Thank you.
做报告
For the speech.
我说了快点  你听得懂吧
When I said rush, I meant, you know, fast.
你们医生都说尽快  对吧
"Stat" is the word you doctors use,right?
我知道这让你为难
I know it's hard for you.
快快快
Double stat?
可能会有点痛
This may sting a little.
-抱歉  -不是打针的原因
- Sorry.- It wasn't the shot.
只是
It's, um-
我头疼的要命
my head's killing me.
参议员  现在没必要做这个
Senator, we don't have to do this now.
可以等到你的HIV测试结果出来
We can hold off till your H.I.V. test comes back.
因为你认定会是阳性结果
Because you figure it's gonna come back positive.
-以我的经验  -病人总是说谎
- In my experience - Patients lie.
政客更是谎话连篇  黑人政客鬼话连篇
Politicians lie more. Black politicians-
我可不认为黑人政客
Oh. I don't think black politicians
比白人政客更能说谎
lie more than white politicians.
我们说谎更少
We lie less.
你认为我们更高尚一些
You figure we're morally superior?
我自有我的理论
I've got my theories.
我们没法逃避
No, we- we just can't get away with it.
没人会为我们作无罪推断
No one's gonna g-give us the benefit of the doubt.
没人会给我们第二次机会
No one's gonna cut us a second chance.
如果出现例外  那就不仅是个坏政客了
And when it happens, it's not just a- a bad politician.
他将是一个道德败坏典型
It's- it's a bad role model.
这将使
It's a- a dis-
我们种族的名誉受损
discredit to the race.
-准备好了吗  -是的
- You ready? - Yeah Yeah
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
豪斯医生  我只想...
Dr. House, I just wanted-
再次心领了
You're welcome again.
我想让你知道我们有多么...
I want you to know how much-
懂了  你们感激涕零
Got it. You're grateful.
而且很明显你以为
Apparently you seem to
你们的感激之情对我意义重大
think it will mean a lot to me to know that.
知道人们为什么向上帝祈祷吗
Do you know why people pray to God?
-我以为你不信上帝  -的确如此
- I thought you didn't believe in God. - I don't.
但愿你能一语惊人
Well, then you better be making a very good point.
你认为人们向他祈祷
Do you think they pray to him and
颂扬他是为了让他知道他的伟大吗
praise him because they want him to know how great he is?
上帝了解自己的伟大
God already knows that.
你是在把我与上帝相提并论吗
Are you comparing me to God?
那很不错  不过我得说清楚
I mean, that's great, but just so you know,
我可从没创造过树木
I've never made a tree.
我感谢你是因为这对我来说意义重大
I thank you because it means something to me...
要为自己所得心怀感恩
to be grateful for what I receive.
你是我见过的最天真的无神论者
You are the most naive atheist I've ever met.
豪斯医生  有位病人在一号房等你
Dr. House, you have a patient in room one.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
人们祈祷是为了上帝不把他们捏死
People pray so that God won't crush them like bugs.
我不会捏死你的
I'm not gonna crush you.
瘀伤
"Petechial" bruising?
不知道是不是叫这个
I don't know if I pronounced that right.
上帝  互联网真是神通广大
Gosh, the Internet is such a wonderful tool.
-可能是白血病  -绝对可能
- It could be leukemia. - Definitely possible.
更有可能是吻痕
The more likely diagnosis is hickey.
不可能是吻痕
Well, it can't be a hickey.
怎么性生活突然变的羞于见人了
Why is everybody so ashamed of sex all of a sudden?
我现在没有性生活
I'm not having sex.
自从离婚以后我就没想过性生活
I've barely even thought about sex since my marriage.
我说你做爱了  你说你没有
I say you're having sex, you say you're not.
要么你在说谎  要么是我诊断错误
Either you're lying or I'm wrong.
-或者有第三种可能  -你指  口交
- Or there's some middle ground. - You mean, like, oral?
我指的是你在不清醒的状态下做爱了
I mean, you're having sex without knowing it.
我要给你做酒精  毒品和γ-羟丁酸的检测
I'm testing you for booze, drugs and G.H.B.
我不喝酒  什么是γ-羟丁酸
I don't drink or-what's G.H.B.?
迷奸药
The date-rape drug.
是阳性
It's positive.
你的T细胞量只有8
Your "T" Cell count is eight,
意味着你很可能会死
which means there's a good chance you'll die.
我告诉你这些
I'm telling you this because
是因为我们要联系你的性伴侣
we need to contact your sexual partners.
自我妻子去世以后
I've only had two girlfriends.
我只交过两个女朋友  两个
Two. After my wife died.
我用避孕套的
I used c-condoms.
你知道戴着避孕套
You know the chances of you getting H.I.V.
与异性性交染上艾滋病的几率多低吗
from heterosexual sex with a condom?
知道
Yes.
或许有一天黑人会当总统
Someday there will be a black president.
或许有一天同性恋会当总统
Someday there will be a gay president.
或许有一天同性恋黑人会当总统
Maybe there'll even be a gay, black president.
但同性恋黑皮肤死人是肯定没有指望的
But one combination I do not see happening is gay, black and dead.
你必须对我说实话
You need to stop lying to me.
总把人往最阴暗的方面想  你一定很痛苦吧
It must be miserable, always assuming the worst in people.
别废话了  你已经病入膏肓了
Cut the crap. You're dying.
你聪明  风趣却是懦夫一个
And you're clever, you're witty and you are a coward.
你害怕冒险
You're scared of taking chances.
我一直都在冒险
I take chances all the time.
-这是我最糟的特质  -对人也是吗
- It's one of my worst qualities. - On people?
对人性本善的愿景并不能使其成为现实
Wanting to believe the best about people doesn't make it true.
害怕相信也不能磨灭其可能性
Being afraid to believe it doesn't make it false.
太感人了  真遗憾我没投票
Well, that's very moving. It's a shame I don't vote.
这就是我  我相信他人
This is who I am. I believe in people.
我不是愤青
I'm not hiply cynical,
不会信口雌黄
and I don't make easy, snide remarks.
哪怕一次次的失望
I would rather think that
我还是愿意相信人性本善
people are good and be disappointed once and again.
我要再抽一点血
I need to draw some more blood.
护士
Nurse!
抗逆转录病毒治疗无效
The antiretrovirals aren't working.
意料之中
That's not surprising.
他会持续恶化
He's just gonna keep getting worse.
你明白的  对吧
You realize that, right?
你干嘛对我的病例探头探脑的
Why are you spying on my case?
那你为什么下周要去做报告
Why are you giving that speech next week?
我们都只是履行职责而已
We're both just doing what we have to do.
你没看出这里面的问题吗
You don't see a problem with that?
关注一个病人有问题吗
Checking in on a patient?
是啊  我该如何自处啊
Yeah, wow. How do I look myself in the mirror?
你不会受他人指使
You're not the one being asked
而去欺骗美国人民
to perpetrate a fraud on the American people.
只是一个十分钟的报告而已
It's a 10-minute speech.
你们逼我就范
That I've been ordered to give.
-沃格勒的药有疗效  -我不管
- Vogler's drug works. - Don't care.
为什么你总是小题大作
Why do you have to make everything so dramatic?
我就是条小疯狗
I'm a very high-strung little lap dog.
别给他用药了
No pills.
怎么回事
What's going on?
抗逆转录病毒药物不起作用
The antiretrovirals aren't working.
为什么
Why not?
因为你没有得艾滋病
Because you don't have AIDS.
第一次的检测结果是假阳性
The first test was a false positive.
5000分之一的发生率
Happens one time in every 5,000.
你做了第二次吗
You r-ran a second test?
-对  -对
- Yeah. - Yeah.
你依然危在旦夕
You're still dying.
唯一的区别是  现在我们不知道病因
The only difference is, now we don't know why.
他的右侧肌力逐渐在丧失
He's continuing to lose control of the muscles on his right side.
大脑意识开始模糊
His brain is getting foggier,
T细胞计数仍是个位数
and his "T" Cells are still in single digits.
我们为何在这里讨论
Why are we doing this here?
这样卡迪就找不到我们了
So Cuddy can't find us.
除非我们能找到潜在的病因
Unless we figure out the underlying disease,
这家伙就对他最后的选民撒谎了
this guy's lied to his last constituent.
艾滋聚合酶链反应检测假阴性吗
False negative on the PCR AIDS test?
做了两次
Ran it twice.
免疫球蛋白缺乏
Immunoglobulin deficiency?
没有呼吸问题的病史
No history of respiratory problems.
先天T细胞不足
Idiopathic "T" Cell deficiency.
先天  拉丁语的意思是
Idiopathic- from the Latin meaning
"我们是傻瓜"  因为我们找不到病因
"We're idiots" 'cause we can't figure out what's causing it.
给他做个全身扫描
Give him a whole body scan.
-你讨厌全身扫描的  -因为没用
- You hate whole body scans. - 'Cause they're useless.
给我们中任何一个做个扫描
Could probably scan any one of us
就能发现5个不同肿瘤疑似物
and find five different doodads that look like cancer.
但橄榄球赛中  完成4次进攻
But when you're fourth down
还有100码要推进  天又下着雪
and a hundred to go, in the snow,
你不会采取带球从中路突破的战术
you don't call a running play up the middle,
除非你是喷气式飞机
unless you're the Jets.
我讨厌拿体育做比喻
I hate sports metaphors.
你为何做了第二次艾滋检测
Why did you order the second AIDS test?
标准程序
Standard procedure.
那么  你是"标准程序先生"了
Oh, well, that's you- Mr. Standard Procedure.
你怀疑第一次检测结果是假阳性
You suspected the first test was a false positive?
我知道他去了非洲
I knew he was going to Africa,
我想他接种了甲肝和乙肝的疫苗
and I figured he was vaccinated for Hep "A" And "B."
可能导致假阳性
That could cause a false positive.
你做第一次检测前就知道了
You knew that before you ordered the first test.
-有什么变化吗  -我该一次做两个的
-What changed? - I should have ordered both.
你曾认准了他患了艾滋
You were sure he had AIDS.
你和他聊天后  你就产生了怀疑
Then you talked to him, then you had doubts.
他说什么了
What did he say?
他说他没有任何危险性行为
He said he had not engaged in any risky behavior.
你相信他了
And you believed him.
他没必要撒谎
He didn't have any reason to lie.
每个人都撒谎  除了政客吗
Everybody lies, except politicians?
豪斯  你还真是个浪漫主义者啊
House, I believe you're a romantic.
你不仅相信他  你还信任他
You didn't just believe him, you believed in him!
今晚你要过来看看老片  擦擦眼泪吗
Do you want to come over tonight and watch old movies and cry?
卡梅隆医生影响了你
Dr. Cameron's getting to you.
我想身处那么多美好事物中
Well, I guess you can't be around that much niceness
必然会受到影响
and not get any on you.
所以你没对她采取行动吗
Is that why you haven't put the moves on her?
你凭什么以为我没对她采取行动
What makes you think I haven't put the moves on her?
老天  你有麻烦了
Boy! You're in trouble.
你让我对人类重拾信心
You have restored my faith in the human race.
-你在撒谎  -不  我没有撒谎
- You're lying. - No. I'm not lying.
刚拿到你的检查报告
Just got your results back.
没有迷奸药  什么也没
No G.H.B., no nothing.
也就是说你有性生活  而你对此撒谎
It means you're having sex and you're lying about it.
不  我有了新的症状
No. And I have a new symptom.
我屁股上出疹子了
I have a rash on my butt.
-你要看看吗  -好
- Do you wanna? - Yeah.
-是什么  -是地毯印
- What is it? - It's a carpet burn.
不  不可能
No. It can't be.
医生  我喜欢做爱
Doctor, I love sex.
我怀念它  我一年都没做过了
I miss it. I haven't had any in over a year.
你能记得这个预约
Well, you managed to keep this appointment,
可见你的短期记忆没问题
so you have no short-term memory problem.
难道是多重人格
Multiple personalities?
你有发现自己忘记干过什么吗
Do you find yourself losing chunks of time?
有没有醒来  却记不得睡着了
Do you wake up, and you don't remember falling asleep?
没有  我就是醒来后觉得非常疲惫
No. I just wake up really exhausted.
-有烦心事吗  -没有
- Something upsetting you? - No.
我前夫住在楼下的公寓里
My ex lives in the apartment downstairs.
他总是给我打电话  要求复合
He's always calling me, always wanting to get back together,
抱怨我口是心非
complaining about mixed signals.
"从我的生活中离开"
"Get out of my life."
"你还不够明白吗"
" How much clearer can you get?
我们地下室有个睡眠实验室
We have a sleep lab in the basement.
起码能让你摆脱前夫一晚
If nothing else, it will get you away from your ex for a night.
左侧腋窝淋巴结略微肿大
Slightly enlarged lymph node in his left armpit.
-多略微  -2.5毫米
- How slightly? - Quarter mil.
-淋巴癌吗  -没错
- Lymphoma? - Sure.
不然就是他六个月内得过感冒
Or he's had a cold in the last six months.
怎么  你把她设在快速拨号了吗
What, you got her on speed dial?
我是嗅着傲慢的气息来的
I just follow the scent of arrogance.
这里有另一个略微肿大的淋巴结
Another slightly enlarged node over here.
外加颈部的两个和腹股沟的一个
Two more in his neck and one in his groin.
肝区还有个囊肿
And there's a cyst in his liver.
看着复杂  中心性坏死吗
It looks complex. Central necrosis?
自发性出血  是良性的
Spontaneous bleeding. It's benign.
我支持有个很酷的肿瘤
I was rooting for a really cool tumor.
不然我们就在这个废物上耗死了
instead we're stuck with this crap.
无所谓  一旦找到它们  就得检查它们
Doesn't matter. Once you find 'em, you gotta check 'em.
把你们累死
Knock yourselves out.
我刚见了怀特参议员
I just saw Senator Wright.
他看着糟糕透顶
He looks like hell.
看来那个寿司比你想的糟得多
That sushi must've been a lot worse than you thought.
沃格勒先生  想要来个免费全身扫描吗
Mr. Vogler, would you like a free whole body scan?
你这体型  一年至少得检查3次
A man of your stature should get himself checked at least three times a year.
这里是一些你在发言中得提到的重点
Here's a few key points I want you to cover during your speech.
14页
Fourteen pages.
听众听到第二段就要昏昏欲睡了
The audience will be comatose by paragraph two.
插个笑话
Throw in a joke.
奇斯医生  我们得谈谈
Dr. Chase, we need to talk.
-你看这事怎么解决  -什么怎么解决
- How do you see this ending? - What ending?
我不能解雇你  所以不用怕我
I can't fire you, so you have no reason to fear me and,
因而也没必要对我撒谎
therefore, no reason to lie to me.
是你告诉卡迪我在哪里
You told Cuddy where I was.
是你告诉沃格勒我在干什么
You told Vogler what I was doing.
-对  -那么我还怎么和你共事
- Yeah. - So how can I work with you?
你别无选择
Well, you don't have a choice.
可能有点疼
This might hurt a little.
骗我吧
Lie to me.
好吧  会像是个柔和的按摩
Okay. It'll feel like a gentle massage.
豪斯
House...
是个差劲的老师
is a lousy teacher.
你不能为了芝麻绿豆大的事撒谎
You can't lie for beans.
你有撒过弥天大谎吗
Have you ever told any really big ones?
我可能很糟糕  但还没迷糊到那个份上
I might be messed up, but I'm not that out of it.
摁下他的手臂
Strap his arm down.
我会没事吗
Am I going to be okay?
但愿如此
I hope so.
我在出卖我的灵魂
I am selling my soul.
就一小块  况且你也不是白白付出
Just a little piece. And you are getting something in return.
我说出卖  没说送人了
I said I was selling it. Didn't say I was giving it away.
不然我真是缺德愚蠢
That would be immoral and stupid.
他们就只加了点抗酸剂
All they've done is add an antacid.
-有用吗  -这不是重点
- Does it work? - That's not the point.
当然是重点  他一没请你撒谎
Of course it's the point. He's not asking you to lie.
二没请你做犯法的事
He's not asking you to do something illegal.
他这根本不是在请我做事
He's not asking me to do anything.
也不是命令你啊
He's not ordering you.
他让你选择  你选择了你的团队
He gave you a choice. You chose your staff.
我知道对你来说不容易  你会痛苦
I know this isn't easy for you. You'll suffer.
泽西的维科丁销量会增至三倍
Vicodin sales in Jersey will triple.
不过你在做好事
But you are doing a good thing.
只有你会觉得做好事很不爽
Only you could feel like crap about doing something good.
肾脏和肝脏的囊肿都是良性的
Kidney and liver cysts are both benign,
而且淋巴结都没有问题
and the lymph nodes all came back clean.
他左侧淋巴结CD11抗体阳性
His left armpit node has antibodies for CD11.
不足以表明是淋巴癌
Not enough to indicate lymphoma.
我们从未检测过毛细胞白血病
We never tested for hairy cell leukemia.
没有  但我们会在淋巴以外
No, but we would have picked it up
其它地方发现的
somewhere else besides one lymph node.
而且他的脾脏没有肿大
And his spleen isn't enlarged.
大小不能代表一切
Size isn't everything.
脾脏是毛细胞的主要来源
The spleen is the mother lode for hairy cells.
开刀
Let's cut it open.
不能活检脾脏  会流血不止的
You can't biopsy his spleen. It'll bleed like stink.
以参议员的状况
In the senator's condition,
脾脏活检很容易引发败血症并致死
a spleen biopsy could easily cause sepsis and kill him.
你为何要对我这样
Why do you do this to me?
现在要是我杀了他
Now if I kill him,
我就不能告诉法官我事先不知道有危险
I can't tell the judge I had no idea of the risks involved.
他的大脑在变成浆糊
His brain is turning into mush,
而且他有更多感染的危险  我们必须做
and he's at risk for more infections. We have to do it.
看见了  在法庭上这么说好多了
See? That'll sound much better in court.
行  去告诉我们的人肉针垫
Okay. Go tell our human pincushion
我们要再多扎他一次
we'll be sticking him one more time.
卡迪
Cuddy.
你不是讨厌这么做吗
Don't you hate doing this?
讨厌
Yeah.
怎么了
What's up?
你喜欢我
You like me.
为什么
Why?
这个问题有点伤感
That's kind of a sad question.
我就是想弄明白你看上我哪点
I'm just trying to figure out what makes you tick.
我不热情也不迷糊
I am not warm and fuzzy,
而你是从小受人呵护的乖宝宝
and you are basically a stuffed animal made by Grandma.
你不是因为这个才问的
I don't think that's why you're asking.
我想是因为那个发言
I think this is because of the speech.
上帝  别把我给分尸了
God, don't try and pick me apart.
那么你为何要问
Then why are you asking?
你想听什么
What do you want to hear?
参议员  我们还要做个脾脏活检
Hey, Senator. We need to do one more biopsy on your spleen.
我不得不用左手签
I'll have to sign lefty.
我的手指不听使唤
My fingers aren't working.
你经常咳嗽吗
Have you been coughing a lot?
疼吗
Does it hurt?
像是我无法呼吸
It's like I can't get air.
是弓浆虫导致的吗
Is that from the toxo?
不  这...这是新症状
No. This is-This is new.
你不用签了  不能做活检
You don't need to sign. We can't do the biopsy.
参议员的呼吸系统严重受损
The senator's breathing is severely impaired.
他的血氧饱和度是89
His O2 sat levels are at 89.
银染显示卡氏肺囊虫肺炎
His silver stain indicates Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia.
另一个致死真菌  和毛细胞白血病相符
Another killer fungus. It's consistent with hairy cell leukemia.
但我们不能活检脾脏  呼吸窘迫
But we can't biopsy his spleen. Respiratory distress.
他的血小板是20  还在下降
His platelets are 20 and dropping.
他的凝血系统不能形成有效血栓
His blood won't clot worth a damn.
一定有其它方法诊断毛细胞
There's gotta be another way to diagnose hairy cell.
不  他的骨髓检测也不能确诊
No. His bone marrow's indeterminate.
只能做脾脏活检
Spleen biopsy's the only way to go.
你知道
You know,
因纽特人钓鱼时  他们不找鱼
when the Inuit go fishing, they don't look for fish.
为什么呢  豪斯医生
Why, Dr. House?
他们找蓝鹭
They look for the blue heron
因为没法看到鱼
because there's no way to see the fish.
但只要有鱼  就会有鸟抓鱼
But if there's fish, there's gonna be birds fishing.
现在  要是他有毛细胞白血病
Now, if he's got hairy cell,
那我们能看到什么在上空盘旋呢
what else should we see circling overhead?
他该有各种少见的病毒
He should have all sorts of weird viruses.
人类嗜T细胞病毒和成人嗜T细胞病毒
H.T.L.V. And A.T.L.V.
我们可以检测它们  做病毒评定
We can test for them. Run the titers.
这些是你大脑在凌晨2:45的脑波
These were your brain waves at 2:45 a.m.
看  慢波睡眠的突然跳跃
Now, here it comes. There's an abrupt jump from slow-wave sleep.
说明你有局部睡眠觉醒
This indicates partial sleep arousal.
最常见的是梦游症  梦游
Most common type is somnambulism. Sleepwalking.
所以我起床时总觉得疲惫
That would explain why I'm so tired when I wake up.
对  也能解释你为何曾怀孕
Yes. And also why you were pregnant.
还有吻痕  还有地毯印
And the hickeys. And the carpet burn.
我睡着的时候做爱了吗
I had sex in my sleep?
睡眠性交是一种失调
Sexsomnia is a documented disorder.
-你说你前夫就住楼下  -我要杀了他
- You said your ex lives downstairs.- I'll kill him.
不过或许他不知道你处于睡眠中
Okay. But he probably didn't know that you were asleep.
睡眠性交与正常情况无异
Sexsomniacs can act pretty normal.
我会给你开低剂量抗抑郁药
I'm gonna write you a prescription for a low-dose antidepressant.
能改善你的睡眠
It'll let you sleep better.
要是你想省下这15块钱
If you wanna save yourself the $15 co-pay,
你可以在醒着的时候做爱
you could have sex while you're awake.
他是我前夫  我不能
He's my ex. I don't-
你们住在一栋楼里
You live in the same building.
一年来你没有和其他人做爱
You haven't had sex with anyone else for a year.
你梦游的时候径直走向他的怀抱
You sleepwalk right into his arms.
说我疯狂  但我觉得你俩前情未了
Call me crazy, but I'm sensing unresolved issues.
人类嗜T细胞病毒1型和2型都是阴性
Negative for H.T.L.V. 1 and 2.
成人嗜T细胞病毒也是阴性  其它都是
And negative for A.T.L.V. And everything else.
不是毛细胞
It's not hairy cell.
你真的要做那个发言吗
Hey. You really gonna give that speech?
-你也有意见吗  -我有点惊讶
- You got an opinion too? - I'm a little surprised.
坦白说  我觉得你是个自私自利的混蛋
Frankly, I thought you were too much of a self-absorbed
不会为我们做这些
ass to do this for us.
不客气  他Eb病毒检测呈阳性
You're welcome. He's positive for Epstein-Barr.
所以
So what?
并不表示是毛细胞  两者毫无关联
It doesn't point to hairy cell. It's irrelevant.
8岁时  你没有从秋千上摔下来
You didn't fall off the swings when you were eight.
6  6  6岁
S-S-Six.
从未
Ever.
-把那个还给我  -我们得谈谈
- Give that back. - We have to talk.
你癫痫发作
You had an epileptic seizure.
所以你咬了自己的舌头
That's how you bit your tongue.
我没有癫痫自从
I haven't had a seizure since-
你用的什么药
What medication did you take?
6岁后就没有发过癫痫
No s-s-seizure since I was six.
10岁后就没有吃药了
No dr-dr-drugs s-since I was 10.
对  就是这个  不用担心问题
Yeah, that's it. Don't worry about what the question is.
你会头晕  不过也不用担心
Don't worry that you're starting to feel dizzy.
只要说实话
Just stay on message.
我的
My-
我妈妈过去叫它
My mother used to call it-
"有趣的东西"
"Funny-something."
-是苯妥因吗  -对
- Phenytoin? - Yes!
好了  好了  没事了
Okay, okay. You're okay.
没事了
It's okay.
每个人都撒谎
Everybody lies.
新泽西参议员加里·H·怀特
Senator Gary H. Wright of NewJersey
患有小儿癫痫
had childhood epilepsy.
他用了苯妥因
He took phenytoin.
该药和Eb病毒共同作用
That drug, with the Epstein-Barr virus,
引发了常见变异型免疫缺陷病
is associated with common variable immunodeficiency disease.
T细胞下降  B细胞下降
"T" Cells down, "B" Cells down.
导致身体无法产生足够抗体
Keeps you from forming enough antibodies.
抗体是防御的根本
See, the antibodies are basically your defensive line.
而你的大脑就像是四分卫
And your brain is like the quarterback.
然后真菌好比
And then the fungi are like
闪电后卫突进到中路
blitzing linebackers plunging up the middle.
你的肺像是
Your lungs are like-
好吧  你有两个四分卫
Okay, you got two quarterbacks.
常见变异型免疫缺陷病吗
C.V.I.D.?
是免疫缺陷的一种  我说过的
That's a type of immunoglobulin deficiency. I said that.
对  你说的时候是个蠢主意
Yeah. Well, it was a stupid idea when you said it.
然后他有了呼吸系统问题
Then he got the respiratory problem,
且Eb病毒检测阳性
and he tested positive for Epstein-Barr.
那个通常是儿童病吧
That's pretty much a childhood disease.
这是另一个说奇斯的建议蠢的缘故
That's another reason why Chase's suggestion was idiotic.
他小时候染上该病
He got it when he was a kid.
直到现在出现症状  有这种情况
He didn't get any symptoms until now. It happens.
由压力引发  比如公开演讲
It gets triggered by stress- like public speaking.
那么你的诊断是基于
So you're basing your diagnosis on a virus
一个常见的病毒和他30年前用的药
that's relatively common and a drug he took 30 years ago.
马上给参议员静注免疫球蛋白
Start the Senator on I.V. immunoglobulin, stat.
若他好转  我对
If he gets better, I'm right.
若死了  你们对
If he dies, you're right.
豪斯医生
Dr. House
-你装的  -没有
-You faked that. -No.
-说"逆转录病毒"  -逆转录病毒
- Say "Antiretroviral". - Antiretroviral.
现在  快速连着说三遍
Now, say it three times fast.
我们刚得到你最新的血检结果
We just got your latest blood results.
你的白细胞计数上升了
Your white cells are up.
你的T细胞计数回到100以上了
Your "T" Cells are back over a hundred.
那个  那个是好事  对吗
That's-That's good, right?
一周之内吗  是奇迹
In a week? That's terrific.
从今往后你都得用药
You'll need medication for the rest of your life,
除此之外  你都没事
but other than that, you're fine.
可以参选总统吗
Am I well enough to run for president?
-怎么不参选教皇呢  -别这样
- Why not run for pope while you're at it? - Oh, come on.
肯尼迪有艾迪生病
Kennedy had Addison's.
富兰克林·罗斯福患有小儿麻痹症
F.D.R. had polio.
他们可是过去百年中两位最伟大的总统
Two of the best presidents in the last hundred years.
要是他们今天参选  门儿都没有
If they were running today, they wouldn't stand a chance.
你觉得若不瘸  将会是卫生部长吗
You figure you'd be surgeon general if you didn't have the limp?
不  有些事我做不了
No. There's things I can't do.
就像你说的  我得接受现实
And like you said, I... have to live with reality.
那么我参选
Well, then I'm running.
真有你的
Good for you.
先别激动  他说的对  我赢不了
Now, don't get excited. He's right. I, uh- I won't win.
那么为什么要参选
Then why run?
我懂  你的意思是
Oh, I see. Your point being,
唯有赢得每一场战斗才谓之有所作为
the only way to make a difference is to win every fight.
为何要听我的
Why listen to me?
我是公司老总  显然信不过  对吗
I own the company. I'm certainly not to be trusted, right?
然而  格雷戈·豪斯医生
Dr. Greg House, on the other hand,
一直以正直著称
has a reputation for integrity, among other things.
女士们先生们  欢迎格雷戈·豪斯医生
Ladies and gentlemen, Dr. Greg House.
东溪医药有着致力于研发的非凡承诺
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals' extraordinary commitment to research excellence...
如他们的新血管紧张素转换酶抑制剂
is exemplified by their new ACE inhibitor,
是医学上的突破
a breakthrough medical approach
将使数百万人远离心脏疾病
that will protect millions from heart disease.
那不是发言
That's not a speech.
我觉得很精练
I thought it was pithy.
不管怎样  写新闻稿足够了
You got enough for a press release anyhow.
福曼还是卡梅隆
Foreman or Cameron.
有几点我忘了说了
A few things I forgot to mention.
爱德·沃格勒是个出色的商人
Ed Vogler is a brilliant businessman,
对人作出英明的评价
a brilliant judge of people...
从未失败过
and a man who has never lost a fight.
你们知道我是如何知道
You know how I know
新血管紧张素转换酶抑制剂有效的吗
that the new ACE inhibitor is good?
因为老的就有效
'Cause the old one was good.
新的其实一样  就是更贵
The new one is really the same, just more expensive.
贵好多
A lot more expensive.
你看  又一个例子说明爱德的才华
You see, that's another example of Ed's brilliance.
当他的药物要丧失专利保护的时候
Whenever one of his drugs is about to lose its patent,
他让他的小喽罗改变
he has his boys and girls alter
药物那么一丁点  就又有专利保护了
it just a tiny bit, patent it all over again,
不仅制造一个毫无意义的新药
making not just a pointless new pill,
还创造了数百万的财富
but millions and millions of dollars.
对大家都好  不是吗
Which is good for everybody, right?
除了病人  不过  谁在乎呢
Except the patients. But- who cares?
他们就是病得太厉害罢了
They're just so damn sick.
反正上帝显然从未垂青他们
God obviously never liked them anyway.
在座各位健康人士
All the healthy people in the room,
让我们向爱德·沃格勒送上热烈的掌声
let's have a big round of applause for Ed Vogler.
我插了个笑话
I threw in a joke.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我该多吃几片维科丁的
I should've taken an extra couple of Vicodin
好克制住自己
and just held my nose.
-我猜你也吃多维科丁了  -没错
- I'm guessing you did take a couple extra Vicodin. - True.
你不用担心解雇谁  我走
You don't need to worry about firing anyone. I'm leaving.
为什么
Why?
又要表现出高尚的自我牺牲的姿态吗
Is this another noble, self-sacrificing gesture?
-你要保护福曼吗  -不
- Are you trying to protect Foreman? - No.
那么就是"不用解雇我  我辞职"吗
So this is just, "Don't fire me. I quit"?
我在保护我自己
I'm protecting myself.
你问我为何喜欢你
You asked me why I like you.
你粗暴无礼
You're abrasive and rude.
但我以为  你做的每件事
But I figured, everything you do,
都是为了帮助别人
you do it to help people.
不过我错了
But I was wrong.
你做  是因为那是正确的
You do it because it's right.
我处理事情只有两个办法
There are only two ways that I can deal with things.
一个是在我控制之中
One is in my control.
另一个就是离开
That's to leave.
再见  豪斯
Good-bye, House.